Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/lindsey-melosphr (LinkedIn) www.uvmhealth.org/medcenter (Company)

Top Skills

Problem Solving

Senior Professional in Human Resources (SPHR)

Human Resources Information Systems (HRIS)

Certifications

Senior Professional in Human Resources (SPHR)

Lindsey Melo, SPHR

Human Resource Professional

Greater Burlington Area

Summary

An established Human Resource professional grounded in the philosophy of positive employee relations. A proven track record of collaboration, trusting relationships, reliability, and persistence to see efforts through to completion. Strong interpersonal skills that allow for positive interactions with leadership, employees, and coworkers. Specialized in Employee relations, leadership coaching, employment law, and workplace investigations. General HR experience including compensation, benefit and 401k plan administration, recruitment, training and development, and ADA and leave management.

Experience

Vermont State University
Assistant Vice President of People and Culture
December 2022 - Present (1 year)

Lead a university-wide HR function, guiding Faculty, Staff, University leaders, and HR managers with respect to employee and labor relations, compliance, recruitment and retention, compensation, performance management, and talent development.

The University of Vermont Medical Center Manager of Employee Relations December 2021 - June 2022 (7 months)

Provided interim leadership to a team in transition, demonstrating professionalism, flexibility, and reliability

University of Vermont Medical Center 16 years

HR Business Partner March 2011 - 2021 (10 years) Burlington, VT Served as a supportive resource to management and staff on regular and complex employee and labor relations issues, using consultative opportunities to build skills and empower those with whom I worked

Lead Benefits Specialist 2005 - February 2011 (6 years) Burlington, VT

Directed the work of a team of benefits professionals administering leave programs such as FMLA, Workers Comp, and disability

Belden Inc. Human Resources Specialist 2004 - 2005 (1 year) Essex, VT

Performed full Human Resource functions of the facility, including benefits administration, leave management, payroll, and employee relations

Champlain Cable Corporation Human Resource Generalist 2000 - 2004 (4 years) Colchester, VT

First point-of-contact for HR-related needs for all employees, including policy and contract interpretation, benefits and 401k administration, recruitment, workers comp administration, and payroll processing

Education

Saint Anselm College B.A.